Duane Family Collection 1764-1933 Mss.SMs.Coll.2
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1764-1933; 1.5 lin. feet
  - ALS to Garret D. Wall, 1827 February 6; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Inquirey as to status of representation (legal counsel) regarding settlement of estate and sale of relsulting lands in Glouster Co. (NJ).
  - ALS to unidentified, 1827 June 27; 2 pgs.; Winchester, George, 1787-1840
    Requests support in financial matter.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1827 September 21; 1 pg.; McLane, Allen, 1786-1845
    Political news.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1828 January 27; 1 pg.; McLane, Louis, 1786-1857
    Asks for assistance in matter of a note on deposit with the Bank of the United States.
  - Articles of agreement:: John Thompson, 1828 May 6; 2 pgs.; Girard, Stephen, 1750-1831
    Thomson agrees (contractually) to be Girard's supervisor regarding his "Land in the Neck."
  - ALS to Allen Trimble, 1828 May 16; 1 pg.; Schulze, John Andrew, 1775-1852
    Sends authenticated copy (missing) of act passed by General Assembly of Pennsylvania, authorizing the Sandy and Beaver canal to extend into Pennsylvania.
  - AQS, a fair copy, to William Duane (1760-1835), 1828 August 21; 2 pgs.; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Critisizes Spannish as a lesser breed of mankind. Asks Duane to recommend a U.S. journal or publication which might publish South American affairs. Mentions theft of his scientific instruments and books, and asks Duane for assistance in replacing them.
    Old catalog number Misc. Ms. Coll. OS
  - ALS to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, 1828 September 20; 2 pgs.; Duane, William, 1760-1835
    Would like to subscribe to Thomas Jefferson's works.
  - ALS to John Adams, 1829 July 31; 2 pgs.; Whitney, R
    Concerns the clarification of resolution of debt.
  - Admission to Court of Common Pleas - Philadelphia, 1830 January 26; 1 pg.; Duane, William, 1808-1882
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1830 February 16; 1 pg.; Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862
    Appoints Duane Director of the Bank of the United States.
    Old catalog number Misc. Ms. Coll. 1970 101ms.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 March 22; 3 pgs.; Duane, Mary and Sarah
    Family news. Mentions death of his friend William Miller in a duel.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 197732ms(2).
  - ALS to William Duane (1760-1835), 1830 March 29; 3 pgs.; Duane, Deborah Bach
    Family news. Relates death of William Miller.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 April 16; 3 pgs.; Duane, Sarah and William John
    Family news. Discussion of the Miller duel and resulting death. William John Duane encloses a draft note (United States bank) for fifty dollars.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms(3).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 April 18; 3pgs.; Duane, Catherine and Deborah
    Family news. Mentions illness of aunt Sally, desire of Catherine to accompany family members to Pittsburgh.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms(4).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 May 18; 3 pgs.; Duane, Sarah
    Family news.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms(5).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 June 11; 2 pgs; Duane, Catherine and Ellen
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms(6).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 June 24; 3 pgs.; Duane, Mary and Sarah
    Old call number B:D852.32. 1977 32ms(7).
  - ALS to Sarah Duane, 1830 July 10; 2 pgs; Duane, William, 1808-1882
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms(8).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 July 14; 2 pgs.; Duane, Catherine
    Family news. Mentions outbreak of scarlett fever.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 32ms(11).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 July 14; 2 pgs.; Duane, Sarah
    Family news. Admonishes William to hurry back to romance a Susan Woodsell? before it is too late (her marriage to another).
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (10).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 July 17; 4 pgs.; Duane, Mary and Sarah
    Family news. Sibling gossip concerning possible romantic matches for William and talk of possible rivals for likely matches in society.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977ms (9).
  - ALS to Mary and Sarah Duane, 1830 July 19; 2 pgs.; Duane, William, 1808-1882
    Family news. Counsels his sisters not to travel to Pittsburgh, as they are unfamiliar with the dangers encounted by those young women out "husband hunting."
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (12).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 August 4; 3 pgs; Duane, Debora, Mary and Sarah
    Family news. Mentions vacation plans.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (13).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 August 20; 3 pgs.; Duane, Mary and Sarah
    Family news. Mentions socializing and romancing of the sisters in Philadelphia society.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (14).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 August 22; 3 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Family news. Mentions dealing with Girard's bank, and characterizations of Steven? Girard.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 August 28; 1 pg; Duane, Catherine
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (15).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 September 1; 4 pg; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Concerns William John Duane's candidacy for congress, ethics (lack therof) in Philadelphia politics, and slander against William Duane. Mentions Henry Clay.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 September 3; 3 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Advice on establishing career in Pittsburgh. News from France, Layfette's role. Mentions Philadelphia politics.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 September 6; 3 pgs.; Duane, Deborah and Ellen
    Family news. Mentions reluctance of William John Duane's reluctance to run for congress.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (16).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 September 22; 4 pgs.; Duane, Mary and Sarah
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (17).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 September 28; 3 pgs; Duane, Catherine and Elizabeth
    Family news. Mentions apprehension in society concerning the French political situation.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (18).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 October 9; 3 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Family news. Philadelphia politics.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1830 December 4; 2 pgs.; Duane, Sarah
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (19).
  - ALS to Sarah Duane, 1830 December 14; 1 pg.; Duane, William, 1808-1882
    Relates boredom, and the "exceedingly dull" nature of the Pittsburgh social scene.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (20).
  - ALS to Henry Clay, [1830]; 2 pgs.; Duane, William, 1760-1835
    Comments on Clay's role in the election, comparing him to Aaron Burr in 1801.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1831 January 7; 3 pgs.; Duane, Sarah
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (21).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1831 January 13; 2 pgs; Duane, Mary
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (22).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1831 January 18; 2 pgs.; Duane, Ellen and Elizabeth
    Family news. Mentions cotillion society parties, and Elizabeth relates news of her tenth birthday.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (23).
  - ALS to Ellen, Elizabeth, Mary, and Sarah Duane, 1831 January 28; 3 pgs.; Duane, William, 1808-1882
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (24).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1831 February 18; 3 pgs.; Duane, Mary and Sarah
    Family news. Mentions parties and impending society marriages.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (25).
  - ALS to Deborah, Mary, and Sarah Duane, 1831 Februrary 25; 1 pg.; Duane, William, 1808-1882
    Old call number B:D852.2 1977 32 (26).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1831 March 7; 2 pgs.; Duane, Deborah and Ellen
    Family news. Mentions William John Duane's appointment to unstated position.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1831 March 11; 3 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    States his intention to travel to Washington to see President Jackson in order to decline the position of Governor Director of the Bank of the United States. Mentions Mr. Girard, Mr. Ryan, and Mr. Simpson.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), [1831] March 13; 4 pgs.; Duane, Catherine and Sarah
    Old call number B:D852.2.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1831 March 17; 2 pgs.; Duane, Elizabeth
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (29).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1831 March 18; 3 pgs.; Duane, Catherine
    Old call number B:D852.2.. 1977 32ms (31).
  - ALS to Justin Butterfield, 1831 March 24; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Testamonial for a John Bell, regarding a draft of music from an estate sale.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1831 March 29; 2 pgs.; Duane, Ellen
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (31).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1831 March 29; 4 pgs.; Duane, Mary and Richard
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (32).
  - ALS to Sarah Duane, 1831 April 5; 1 pg.; Duane, William, 1808-1882
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (33).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1831 April 10; 3 pgs.; Duane, Sarah
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (34).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1831 May 9; 3 pgs.; Duane, Mary
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (35).
  - ALS to Sarah and William John Duane, 1831 May 13; 1 pg.; Duane, William, 1808-1882
    Family news. Asks for $30.00 to cover his expenses in traveling to Philadelphia to visit family.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (36).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), [1831]; 4 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Gives reasons for not accepting President Jackson's appointment.
  - ALS to the Select of Common Councils of the City of Philadelphia, 1833 February 9; 1 pg.; Cope, Thomas Pim, 1768-1854
    Asks to be excused from consideration as a candidate for trustee of Girard College.
  - ALS to Willaim John Duane, 1833 February 13; 1 pg.; Ingraham, Edward Duffield, 1802-1891
    Acknowledgement of an offer to sign an amicus brief in a legal case.
  - ALS to Committee of Insolvency (Philadelphia), 1833 June 3; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Writing as Secretary of Treasury, concerning insolvency of Benjamin F. Johnson regarding the feasibility of case against him.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1833 June 8; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    News of legal business.
  - ALS to Samuel Brooks, 1833 June 21; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Comments on whether his son's (William Duane Jr.) professional prospects will justify his marriage (to Louise Brooke; 6 Nov. 1833) next fall.
  - AQC, a fair copy, to William John Duane, 1833 June 26; 3 pgs.; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845
    Jackson directs Duane as Secretary of the Treasury to discontinue the Bank of the United States, and direct (Discretely) the deposits on hand to state banks in Pennsylvania, Maryland, Georgia, South Carolina, and Alabama.
    Old call number B:D852.1. 1974 4147ms.
  - AQC, a fair copy, William John Duane, 1833 June 26; 17 pgs.; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845
    Jackson's entire policy regarding proposed closure of the Bank of the United States.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1833 July 1; 1 pg.; Kendall, Amos, 1789-1869
    Reference letter for a James Owner for the position of clerk in the Department of Treasury.
  - ALS to William Duane, Jr., 1833 July 8; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Responds to son's anxiety regarding William John Duane's position in the Bank of the United States situation. Mentions the "folks at Bush Hill," scorning their malice and envy.
  - [copy] letter unsigned to Andrew Jackson, 1833 July 10; 17 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Refuses Jackson's order, refutes his points in order.
  - [copy] letter unsigned to Andrew Jackson, 1833 July 12; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Acknowledges receipt of note (same day), and will forward report to Jackson. Mentions sending deposits of Bank of the United States to an alternative depository.
  - [Copy] letter unsigned to Willian John Duane, 1833 July 17; 11 pgs.; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845
    Response to Duane's objections to his policy of de-regulation of the Bank of the United States, and dispersal of funds to state banks.
  - Memorandum of agreement with Robert Jones., 1791 May 3; 2 pgs.; Duane, William, 1760-1835
  - [Copy] letter unsigned to Andrew Jackson., 1833 July 19; 12 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Explanation of reasons not to close Bank of the United States.
  - AQS, a fair copy, to William John Duane, 1833 July 22; 3 pgs.; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845
    Response to Duane that attempts to clarify Jackson's desire to close the bank of the United States as either a part of the Federal govt., or state banks.
  - AQS, a fair copy, to William John Duane, 1833 July 22; 2 pgs.; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845
    Jackson asserts his authority, and demands that Duane follow his instructions to begin proceedings designed to transfer monies to state banks.
  - AQS, a fair copy, to William John Duane, 1833 July 23; 1 pg.; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845
    Returns the draft of the instruction on the bank closure, with minor edits.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1833 August 16; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Advice on Philadelphia politics. Mentions his own situation relating to "mattter of great consequence."
  - ALS to Andrew Jackson, 1833 September 8; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    States that his corrections to his report to Jackson in no way constitutes "no cause for a change of depository" arrangement.
    Old call number B:D852.1. Contains a previous draft on reverse.
  - [Copy] letter unsigned to Andrew Jackson, 1833 September 9; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Submits report of agents evaluation of whether state banks would submit to federal authority.
  - ALS to William Duane (1807-1882), 1833 September 12; 2 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Personal and political news of Washington. Expects to be sent home (dismissed) from his position soon. Advice on how to begin married life.
  - ALS to A. J. Donelson, 1833 September 19; 1 pg,; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Objects publication (in the Globe) of announcement by Jackson that federal monies would be removed to state banks--befor Duane had issued his approval or rejection of said action.
  - AQS, a fair copy, to Andrew Jackson, 1833 September 19; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Asks Jackson for one day before giving his official decision regarding the Bank of the United States, so as to be able to counsel ("As I have not a friend here to advise with") with his father.
    Old call number B:D852.1. 1974 1471ms. Contains note of Duane's actions.
  - ALS to Andrew Jackson, 1833 September 21; 10 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Duane refuses to use position of Secretary of the Treasury to close the Bank of the United States. Mentions his refusal to resign.
    Old call number B:D852.1. 1974 1471ms. Includes enclosures, 4 separate copies of prior letters.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1833 September 21; 1 pg.; Donelson, Andrew Jackson, 1799-1871
    Sends notice that the President requires the paper containing his decision of the deposits.
  - ALS? to Andrew Jackson, 1833 September 21; 3 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Unequivical refusal to move public monies from the Bank of the United States. Cites a summary of events ana correspondence that led to this point.
  - ALS to Andrew Jackson, 1833 September 21; 3 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Summary and copies of correspondence Sept. 18-20.
  - ALS to Andrew Jackson, 1833 September 21; 3 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Clarifies position: that in earlier communication he was not equivicating in his refusal to transfer public monies from the Bank of the United States. Reiterates position, "I refuse to aid, assist, or in any way participate in the proposed changes..."
  - ALS to A. J. Donelson, 1833 September 22; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Note accompanying letter sent day prior (backdated). Mentions his father's proofreading and consultations regarding matter of decision regarding Duane's refusal to agree with Jackson's intent to withdraw public money from bank.
  - ALS to A. J. Donelson, 1833 September 27; 2 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Farewell letter to Donelson. Mentions dissapointment with Donelson in avoiding seeing him in person.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1833 September 29; 9 pgs.; Donelson, Andrew Jackson, 1799-1871
    Explains why he was unable to meet with Duane. Mentions Jackson's lack of enmity towards Duane, regret concerning turn of events.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1833 October 24; 2 pgs.; Taney, Roger Brooke, 1777-1864
    Thanks Duane for "friendly letter." Clarifies his position (denies) regarding press reporting his establishment of extra-constitutional bureau with the Treasury dept.
  - ALS to James Buchanan, 1833 November 17; 1 pg.; Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844
    Invitation to dinner.
  - Opinions regarding Bank of the United States, [1833]; 6 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Includes R. B. Taney's opinion of deposit question.
    Old call number B:D852.1. 1974 1471ms. Hand transcribed opinions copied from newspapers and other sources.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1834 January 16; 2 pgs.; Nixon, Fleming
    Letter of support, regarding Duane's stance in the Bank of the United States matter.
    Old call number B:D852.1. 1974 1471ms. A copy of Duane's response is on same letter.
  - ALS to Fleming Nixon, 1834 January 27; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Thanks citizens of Loudon county for their support.
    Old call number B:D852.1. 1974 1471ms. Hand transcribed copy on original from Nixon from 1834 Jan. 16.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1834 March 13; 3 pgs.; Gordon, Robert A
    Letter of support.
  - ALS to John Vaughan, 1834 February 27; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Declines official portrait as member (former) of Jackson's cabinent. Claims a portrait reflects a conceited nature.
    Old catalog number Misc. Ms. Coll.
  - ALS to Robert A.. Gordon, 1834 March 26; 4 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Thanks Gordon and citizens of his county for their sentiments. Mentions Jackson in less than flattering terms.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1834 March 26; 4 pgs.; Mayr, George Louis
    Letter of support from the Union Committee of Lancaster, PA.
  - ALS to the Commercial Intellingencer, 1834 March 29; 3 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Writes to the Commercial Intellingencer, disputing the offical account of the Bank of the United States affair printed in the "President's official paper," the Globe.
    Old call number B:D852.1. 1974 1471ms. Includes clipping from The Globe (newspaper).
  - ALS to George Lewis Meyer, 1834 March 29; 2 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Thanks Union Committee of Lancaster, PA. For their letter of support on the 26th.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1834 March 29; 3 pgs.; Mechanics of the city of Troy, New York
    Letter of support, re: Bank of the United States.
    Old call number B:D852.1. 1974 1471ms. Includes clipping.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1834 May 10; 2 pgs.; Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852
    Thanks for a copy of a pamphlet. Salutes Duane for his sense of duty.
    Old call number B:D852.1. 1957 1344ms (Deposit).
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1834 May 28; 1 pg.; Wallace, George Y
    Letter of support from the citizens of Portage County, Ohio.
    Old call number B:D852.1. 1974 1471ms. Includes clipping of Duane's response.
  - ALS to Sarah Duane, 1835 April 6; 2 pgs.; Duane, William, 1808-1882
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (37).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1835 April 13; 2 pgs.; Duane, Sarah
    Family and society news.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (38).
  - ALS to William John Duane?, 1835 August 31; 2 pgs.; Harwood, Andrew Allen, 1802-1884
    Business (legal) matter.
  - ALS to J. M. Campbell, 1836 March 9; 1 pg.; Taney, Roger Brooke, 1777-1864
    Mentions Taney's confirmation.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1836 March 12; 1 pg.; Galbraith, John, 1794-1860
    Business (legal) correspondence.
  - ALS to J. P. [Stetly], 1836 March 12; 1 pg.; Hays, J.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1837 March 6; 2 pgs.; Peyton, Balie, 1803-1878
    Offers to send Duane the minority report from congress?
  - ALS to Lewis J. Cist, 1837 April 6; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Encloses signature of Stephen Girard, along with testimonial as to Girard's character.
    Old call number B:D852.3. Includes clipping of Duane's obituary from 1863.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1837 May 31; 2 pgs.; McKean, Samuel, 1787-1841
    Encloses packet of six letters originally from the President (June 26-Sept. 21, 1833).
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1837 July 4; 1 pg.; Forward, Walter, 1786-1852
    Political news. Mentions Forward halting a publication.
  - ALS to Levi Woodbury, 1837 July 7; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Writes to the Secretary of the Treasury requesting a letter left behind in a larger packet of letters at the Treasury from his (Duane's) tenure as Secretary.
  - ALS to Sarah Duane, 1837 September 11; 3 pgs.; Duane, William, 1808-1882
    News of his trip to Illinois. Mentions local geography, potential for building wealth. Asks for a tailor to make him some work pants.
    Old call number B:D852.2. 1977 32ms (39).
  - ALS to James T. Hale, 1837 October 13; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1838 April 5; 3 pgs.; Harwood, Andrew Allen, 1802-1884
    Requests that Duane sell his Race steet lot.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1838 November 5; 1 pg.; Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
    Receipt of a manuscript, "Accounts of the Overseerers of the Poor of the City of Philadelphia from March 29, 1758 to March 21, 1759." Transcribed from original by Duane. Officiating historical society officer: Peter Du Ponceau.
  - ALS to John Vaughan, 1839 February 7; 1 pg.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Presents F. Hoskins paper on navigation, which was dedicated to Thomas Jefferson, to the American Philosophical Society.
    Old catalog number Misc. Ms. Coll. Unlocated as of 11/28/07.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1839 June 26; 1 pg.; Bancroft, George, 1800-1891
    Acknowledgement of letter received on the fourth. Praises Duane's Journal.
  - ALS to William Duane (1808-1882), 1840 January 22; 1 pg.; Ingraham, Edward Duffield, 1802-1891
    Dinner invitation
  - ALS to James Buchanan and William S. Ramsay, 1840 March 4; 1 pg.; U.S. War Department
    Application on behalf of William Duane for the position of Visitor to the Military Academy.
  - ALS to John G. Clark, 1840 March 21; 2 pgs.; Duane, William John, 1780-1865
    Concerns disposition of Stephen Girard's will.
  - Marriage contract between George V. Huddleston and Hannah C. Brackenridge, 1840 July 1; 4 pgs.; Duane, William, 1808-1882
    Marriage contract which names Duane as executor named to be in charge of all assets (estate in trust) of Brackenridge received from George Bartram's estate.
    Old call number B:D852.1. 1974 1471ms. Oversize.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1841 January 2; 2 pgs.; Ingersoll, Charles Jared, 1782-1862
    Concerns national politics. Enjoyed his publication on education.
  - ALS to Lewis Cist, 1841 September 11; 2 pgs.; Woodbury, Levi, 1789-1851
    Response to query concerning politicians descendents.
  - ALS to William John Duane, 1841 Nov. 2; 3 pgs.; Denny, Barry
    Family news. Mentions Charles Wall, Senior Fellow of Dublin College. Would like ring as token of friendship.